<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Articles to be inquired of, in the [f]irst metropoliticall visitation, of the most reuerend father, George, by Gods pro[v]idence, Arch- bishop of Canterbury, and primate of all England in, and for the dioces of Peterbury, in the yeare of our Lord God, 1613 and in the third yeare of His Graces translation.</title>
            <author>Church of England. Province of Canterbury. Archbishop (1611-1633 : Abbot)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1613</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 36 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 10 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A00244</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 10314.7</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S2101</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">23026953</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 23026953</idno>
            <idno type="VID">26106</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A00244)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 26106)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1795:48)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Articles to be inquired of, in the [f]irst metropoliticall visitation, of the most reuerend father, George, by Gods pro[v]idence, Arch- bishop of Canterbury, and primate of all England in, and for the dioces of Peterbury, in the yeare of our Lord God, 1613 and in the third yeare of His Graces translation.</title>
                  <author>Church of England. Province of Canterbury. Archbishop (1611-1633 : Abbot)</author>
                  <author>Abbot, George, 1562-1633.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[15] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by VVilliam Iaggard,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1613]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Date of imprint suggested by STC (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Signatures: A-B⁴.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: tightly bound.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Lambeth Palace Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Church of England --  Pastoral letters and charges.</term>
               <term>Visitations, Ecclesiastical --  England.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:26106:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>ARTICLES To be inquired of, in the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>ſt Metropoliticall viſitation, of the moſt <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>euerend Father, GEORGE, by Gods <hi>pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>ence, Arch-Bishop of Canterbury, and Primate of all</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>gland; in, and for the Dioces of Peterbury, in the yeare of our Lord God, 1613 and in the third yeare of his Graces Tranſlation.</p>
            <figure>
               <q>HEB DDIM HEB DDIEV</q>
               <figDesc>printer's device of William Jaggard</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>LONDON, Printed by William Iaggard.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="oath">
            <pb facs="tcp:26106:2"/>
            <head>The Tenor of the Oath, to be Miniſtred to the Church-wardens <hi>and Side-men.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>YOu ſhall ſweare, that you, and euery of you, ſhall dulie conſider, and diligently enquire, of all and euery of theſe Articles giuen you in charge; and that all affection, fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uour, hatred, hope of reward and gain, or feare of diſpleaſure, or mallice ſet aſide; you ſhall preſent all and euery ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, of, or within your Pariſh, as hath committed any offence, or made any default mentioned in theſe, or any of theſe Arti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cles; or which are vehemently ſuſpected or defamed of any ſuch offence or default: Wherein you ſhal deale vprightly and fully; neither preſenting, nor ſparing to preſent any, co<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="5 letters">
                  <desc>•••••</desc>
               </gap> to truth: hauing in this action God before your eyes, with an earneſt zeale to maintaine truth, and to ſuppreſſe vice. So help you God, and the holie Contents of this Booke.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:26106:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>¶ Concerning the Church, the Ornaments thereof, and the Churches poſſeſſions.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>Mprimis,</hi> whether haue you in your ſeuerall Churches and Chappels, the whole Bible of the largeſt volume, and the Booke of Common Prayer, lately ſet forth by his Maieſties authoritie, both fairely and ſubſtantiallie bound: a Font of Stone, ſet vp in the auncient vſuall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ace: a conuenient and decent Communion Table, with a Carpet of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ilke, or ſome other decent ſtuffe, continuallie laide vpon the Table at <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ne of Diuine ſeruice, and a faire Linnen cloath vpon the ſame, at the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ne of the receiuing of the holy Communion. And whether is the ſame <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ble placed in ſuch conuenient ſort within the chancell or church, as that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he Miniſter may be beſt heard in his Prayer and adminiſtration, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hat the greateſt number may communicate: And whether is it ſo vſed <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> of time of Diuine ſeruice, as is not agréeable to the holy vſe of it; as <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>atting on it, throwing Hats on it, writing on it, or is it abuſed to other <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>phaner vſes: and are the Ten Commaundements ſet vpon the Eaſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>d of your church or chappell where the people may beſt ſée and reade <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>un, and other ſentences of holy Scripture, written on the walles like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ſe for that purpoſe?</p>
            <p n="2">2 <hi>Item,</hi> whether haue you in your ſaid church or chappell, a conueni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> ſeat for your Miniſter to read ſeruice in, together, with a comely pul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> ſet vp in a conuenient place, with a decent cloath or cuſhion for the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>e, a comely large Surplice, a faire Communion cup, with a couer of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>uer, a Flaggon of Siluer, Tinne, or Pewter, to put the Wine in, hereby it may be ſet vpon the Communion Table, at the time of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>eſſing thereof, with all other thinges and ornaments neceſſarie for the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>bration of Diuine Seruice, and adminiſtration of the Sacraments? <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd whether haue you a ſtrong Cheſt for Almes for the poore, with thrée <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ckes and Keies, and another cheſt for kéeping the Bookes, and Orna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ents of the Church, and the Regiſter Booke. And whether haue you a <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>egiſter Booke in Parchment, for Chriſtnings, Weddings, and Buri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>, and whether the ſame be kept in all pointes, according to the Can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nons
<pb facs="tcp:26106:3"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb facs="tcp:26106:3"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb facs="tcp:26106:4"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb facs="tcp:26106:4"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb facs="tcp:26106:5"/>
in that behalfe prouided? And whether haue you in your ſaide Church or Chancell, a Table ſet, of the degrées wherein by Law Men are prohibited to marry?</p>
            <p n="3">3 Whether are your Church and Chappels, with the Chancels ther<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, and your parſonage or vicarage houſe, your Pariſh Almes-houſe and Church-houſe, in good reparations: and are they imployed to godly, and the r<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ght holy vſes? Is your Church, Chancell, and Chappell decently and comely kept, as well within as without, and the ſeats well maintai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned, according to the 85. Cannon, in that behalfe prouided? Whether your Church-yard be well fenced, and kept without abuſe: and if not, in whoſe default the ſame is, and what the defect or fault is? and whether any perſon haue incroached vpon the ground of the Church-yard, or whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther any perſon or perſons, haue vſed any thing or place conſecrated to ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly vſe, prophanely or wickedly?</p>
            <p n="4">4 Whether haue you the Terrier of all the Gleabe Lands, Medowes, Gardens, Orchards, Houſes, Stockes, Implements, Tenements, and portions of Tiths (whether within your Pariſh or without) belonging vnto your parſonage or vicarage, taken by the view of honeſt men in your ſaid Pariſh? And whe her the ſame Terrier be laid vp in the Biſhoppes Regiſtery, and in whoſe hands any of them are now. And if you haue no Terrier already made in Parchment, you the Church-wardens &amp; Side<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, together with your Parſon or Vicar, or in his abſence, with your Miniſter, are to make diligent inquiry and preſentment of the premiſes, and make, ſubſcribe, and ſigne, the ſaid Terrier, as aforeſaid?</p>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Concerning the Miniſters.</head>
               <p n="1">1 VVHether doth your Miniſter, diſtinctly and reuerently ſay Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uine ſeruice vpon Sundayes and Holidaies, and other daies appointed to be obſerued by the booke of Common Prayer: as Wedneſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dayes, and Fridaies and the eeues of euery Sunday and Holiday, at ſi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> and vſuall times? And doth your Miniſter duely obſerue the Orders Rites, and Ceremonies, preſcribed in the ſaid Booke of Common Pray<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>er, as well in reading publike prayers and the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>etany, as alſo in admi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>niſtring the Sacraments, ſolemnization of Matrimony, viſiting the ſick burying the dead, Churching of Women, and all other like Rites an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Offices of the Church, in ſuch manner and forms, as in the ſaid Book of Common prayer he is inioyned, without any omiſſ on or addition And doth hee read the Booke of the laſt Cannons once yearely, and wear<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> a Surplice according to the ſaid Cannons?</p>
               <p n="2">2 Doth your Miniſter bid Holidaies and Faſting-daies, as by th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb facs="tcp:26106:5" rendition="simple:additions"/>
Boke of Common Prayer is appointed? And doth he giue warning be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore hand to the Pariſhioners, for the receiuing of the holy Communion, as the 22. Cannon requireth? And whether he doth adminiſter the holy Communion ſo often, and at ſuch times, as that euery Pariſhioner may receiue the ſame, at the leaſt thrice in euery yeare: whereof once at Ea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter, as by the Booke of common Prayer is appointed? And doth your Miniſter receiue the ſame himſelfe, on euery day that he adminiſtreth it to others, and vſe the wordes of inſtitution, according to the Booke, at euery time that the Breade and Wine is renewed; accordingly as by the Prouiſo of the 21. Cannon, is directed? And doth hée deliuer the Bread and Wine to euery Communicant ſeuerally? Whether hée hath admitted to the holy Communion any Offendor, or Schiſmaticke, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to the 26. and 27. conſtitutions, or receiued any to the communion beeing not of his owne cure, or put any from the Communion, who are not publiquely infamous for any notorious crime? Doth hée vſe the ſigne of the Croſſe in Baptiſme, or Baptize in any Baſon, or other Veſſel, and not in the vſuall Font? Or admit any Father to bee God-Father to his owne child, or ſuch which haue not receiued the holy Communion: or Baptiſe any children that were not borne in the pariſh; or wilfully refuſe to baptiſe any Infant in his Pariſh beeing in danger, hauing béene enfor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med of the weakeneſſe of the ſaid child: and whether the ſaide child dyed through his default, without Baptiſme?</p>
               <p n="3">3 Whether hath your Miniſter married any without a King, or without Banes publiſhed thrée ſeuerall Sundaies or Holidaies in time of Diuine ſeruice, in the ſeuerall churches or chappels of their ſeuerall a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bode, according to the Booke of common Prayer, or in times prohibited, albeit the Banes were thrice publiſhed, without a Licenſe or diſpenſati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on f<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>om the Arch-biſhop, the Biſhop of the Dioceſſe, or his Chancellor; firſt obtained in that behalfe? Or not betwixt the houſes of eight and twelue in the forenoone, or haue married any in any priuate houſe, or if the parties be vnder the age of twenty one yeares, before their Parents or Gouernours haue ſignified their conſent vnto him?</p>
               <p n="4">4 Doth he refuſe to bury any, which ought to be inferred in chriſtian burial, or deferre the ſame longer then he ſhould, or bury any in chriſtian buriall, which by the conſtitutions of the church of England ought not ſo to be interred?</p>
               <p n="5">5 Is your Miniſter, a Preacher allowed? If yea; then by whom, if not? Whether dooth he procure ſome who are lawfully licenſed, to preach monthly amongſt you at the leaſt?</p>
               <p n="6">
                  <pb facs="tcp:26106:6" rendition="simple:additions"/>6 Doth your Miniſter (being licenced) preach vſually according to the Cannons, either in his owne Cure, or in ſome other church or chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pell néere adioyning, where no Preacher is, and how often he hath béene negligent in that behalfe, and doth he preach ſtanding, and with his hat off? Or whether doth he or his Curate vpon euery Sunday, when there is no Sermon, read an Homilie, or ſome part thereof, according as hée ought to doe; or in caſe he be not licenſed to preach, doth he take vpon him to Preach or expound the Scriptures in his owne Cure, or elſe-where; If ſo, then you are to preſent the ſame, the time and place, when, and where he did it?</p>
               <p n="7">7 Doth your Miniſter vſe to pray for the Kinges Maieſty, King <hi>Iames,</hi> and for the Quéenes Maieſty, the Prince, and all their Royall Progeny, with addition of ſuch ſtile and Titles as are due to his High<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſe, and exhort the people to obedience to his Maieſty, and all Magi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrates in authority vnder him?</p>
               <p n="8">8 Is your Miniſter continually reſident vppon his Benefice, and how long time hath he beene abſent, and in caſe he be licenſed to bee ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent; whether doth he cauſe his Cure to be ſufficiently ſupplied, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the Cannons: or in caſe he hath another Benefice, whether doth he ſupply his abſence by a Curate, ſufficiently licenſed to preach in that Cure where he himſelfe is not reſident. Or otherwiſe, in caſe the ſmal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſe of the Liuing cannot finde a Preaching Miniſter, doth he preach at both his Benifices vſually?</p>
               <p n="9">9 Doth your Miniſter or Curate, ſerue any more Cures then one: if yea, then what other Cure, dooth hee ſerue, and how farre are they di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant?</p>
               <p n="10">10 Doth your Miniſter euery Sunday and Holliday, before Eue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning Prayer, for halfe an houre or more, examine and inſtruct the youth and ignorant perſons of his Pariſh, in the Ten Commaundements, Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticles of the Beléefe, and in the Lords Prayer, and the Sacrament, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording as it is preſcribed in the Catechiſme, ſet foorth in the Booke of Common Prayer?</p>
               <p n="11">11 Doth your Miniſter in the Rogation daies, goe in perambulati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the circuit of the Pariſh, ſaying and vſing the Prayers, Suffra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges, and Thankſgiuing to God, appointed by Law, according to his du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, thanking God for his bleſſinges, if there be plenty on the earth; Or otherwiſe, to pray for his grace and fauour, if there be a feare of ſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ſitie?</p>
               <p n="12">12 Hath your Miniſter admitted any Woman, begotten with child in Adultry or Fornication, to be churched without licenſe of the ordinary?</p>
               <p n="13">
                  <pb facs="tcp:26106:6"/>13 Hath your Miniſter or any other Preacher, baptized Children, churched any woman, or miniſtred the holy Communion in any priuate houſe, otherwiſe then as by Law is allowed?</p>
               <p n="14">14 Doth your Miniſter, being a Preacher, endeuour and labour di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligently to reclaime the Popiſh Recuſants in his Pariſh from their er<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rors, (if there bee any ſuch abiding in your Pariſh.) Or whether is your Parſon, Vicar, or Curate, ouer conuerſant with, or a fauourer of Recu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſants, whereby he is ſuſpected not to be ſincere in Religion?</p>
               <p n="15">15 Hath your Miniſter taken vpon him, to appoint any publique or priuate Faſts, Propheſies, or exerciſes, not approued by Law, or pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like authority, or hath vſed to méete in any priuate houſe or place, with any perſon or perſons, there to conſult how to impeach or depraue the book of common prayer, or the Doctrine or Diſcipline of the Church of Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land: If yea, then you ſhall preſent them all?</p>
               <p n="16">16 Hath your Miniſter ſtated the publication of any excommuni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cations or ſuſpitions, or doth he euery halfe yeare denounce in his Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh-church, all ſuch of his Pariſh as are excommunicated, and perſeuer therein without ſeeking to be abſolued, or doth he wittingly and willing<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly kéep company with ſuch as are excommunicate: And hath he admitted into your Church, any perſon excommunicate, without a Certificate of his abſolution from the Ordinary, or other competent Iudge?</p>
               <p n="17">17 Doth your Miniſter carefully looke to the reléefe of the poore, and from time to time call vpon his Pariſhioners to giue ſomewhat, as they can ſpare, to godlie and charitable vſes, eſpecially when they make their Teſtaments?</p>
               <p n="18">18 Whether your Miniſter or any, hauing taken holy orders, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing now ſilenced or ſuſpended, or any other perſon of your knowledge, or as you haue heard, hold any conuenticles, or doth preach in any place, or vſe any other forme of Diuine ſeruice then is appointed in the Booke of Common praier: If yea, then you are to preſent their names, and with whom?</p>
               <p n="19">19 Whether is your Curate licenſed to ſerue, by the Biſhop of this Dioceſſe, or by any other, and by whom?</p>
               <p n="20">20 Doth your Miniſter vſe ſuch decency and comelineſſe in his ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parrell, as by the 47. Cannon is enioyned: and is he of ſober behauiour, and one that doth not vſe ſuch bodily labour, as is not ſéemely for his ſun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion and calling?</p>
               <p n="21">21 Is your Miniſter noted or defamed, to haue obtained his Beni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice or his orders, by Symony, or any other way defamed, to be Symo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niacall
<pb facs="tcp:26106:7" rendition="simple:additions"/>
perſon, or any way noted to bee a Schiſmaticke, or ſciſmaticallie affected or reputed to be an incontinent perſon, or doth table or lodge any ſuch in his houſe: or is he a frequenter of Tauernes, Innes, or Ale-hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, or any place ſuſpected for ill rule: Or is he a common Drunkard, a common Gamſter, or player at Dice, a Swearer, or one that applyeth himſelfe not at his ſtudy, or is otherwiſe offenſiue and ſcandalous to his function or Miniſtry?</p>
               <p n="22">22 Doth your Preacher or Lecturer read Diuine ſeruice, and Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter the Sacraments twice a yeare at leaſt in his own perſon, according to the Cannons?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Schoole-Maiſters.</head>
               <p n="23">23 DOth any in your Pariſh take vpon him to teach Schoole, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Licenſe of the Ordinary, and is he conformable to the Reli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gion now eſtabliſhed? And doth he bring his Schollers to the Church, to heare Diuine ſeruice, and Sermons? And doth he inſtruct his Shol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lers in the groundes of the Religion now eſtabliſhed in this Church of England, and is he carefall and diligent to benefit his Schollers in lear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Pariſh Clearkes and Sextons.</head>
               <p n="24">24 HAue you a fit Pariſh Clark, aged twenty yeares at leaſt, of ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſt conuerſation, able to read and write? whether are his and the Sextons wages paid without fraud, according to the ancient cuſtome of your Pariſh: if not, then by whom are they ſo defrauded or denyed? By whom are they choſen? And whether the ſaid Clarke be approued by the Ordinary? And hath he taken an Oath, as in ſuch caſes is fit and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired: And is he diligent in his office, and ſeruiceable to the Miniſter, and doth he take vpon him to meddle with any thing aboue his Office: as Churching of Women, burying the dead, or ſuch like?</p>
               <p n="25">25 Doth your Clarke or Sexton kéepe the Church cleaue, the doores locked? Is any thing loſt or ſpoyled in the Church, through his default? doth he ſuffer any vnſeaſonable ringing, or any prophane exerciſe in your Church? Or doth he (when any is paſſing out of this life) neglect to tole a Bell, hauing notice thereof.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Concerning the Pariſhoners.</head>
               <p n="1">1 VVHether any of your Pariſhoners, béeing ſixtéene yeares of age or vpwards, or others lodging or commonly reſorting to any Houſe within your Pariſh, do wil<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ullie abſent themſelues from your Pariſh-church, vpon Sondaies or Holidaies at Morning and Euening Prayers? Or who come late to Church, and depart from church, before
<pb facs="tcp:26106:7" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ruice be done vpon the ſaid daies? Or who doe not reuerently behaue <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>emſelues during the time of Diuine Seruice, deuoutly knéeling, when <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e generall confeſſion of ſinnes, the Letany, the ten Commandements, and all Prayers and Collects are read, and vſing all due and lowly reue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>nce, when the bleſſed name of the Lord Ieſus Chriſt is mentioned, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>tanding vp when the Articles of the Beleefe are read; or who doe couer <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>heir heads in the Church during the time of Diuine ſeruice, vnleſſe it be a caſe of neceſſity, in which caſe they may weare a Night-cap or coy<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e? Or who doe giue themſelues to babling, talking, or walking, and are <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ot attentiue to heare the word preached, or read; or reading, or praying, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ring the time aforeſaid? Whether any of your Pariſh being of ſixtéen yeares of age or vpwards, doe not receiue the holie communion in your <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hurch thrice euery yeare; whereof once at Eaſter, and whether they <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>e not deuoutly kneele at the receiuing thereof?</p>
               <p n="2">2 Whether any of your Pariſhioners, being admoniſhed thereof, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>e not ſend their Children, Seruants, and Apprentizes, to the Miniſter, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> be catechized vppon ſuch Sondaies and Holidaies as are appointed? Or whether any of them doe refuſe to come; or if they come, refuſe to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ne thoſe inſtructions ſet forth in the Booke of common prayer?</p>
               <p n="3">3 Whether any of your pariſh doe entertaine within their houſe, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>y ſoiourner, common gueſts or other perſons, who refuſe to frequent <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>iuine ſeruice or receiue the holie communion, as aforeſaide? preſent <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>eir names, their qualities, or conditions.</p>
               <p n="4">4 What Recuſant Papiſts are there in your pariſh? preſent their <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>nes, qualities, or conditions? whether kéepe they any Schoolemaiſter <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> their houſe, which commeth not to church to heare Diuine ſeruice and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>trine the Communion? What is his Name, and how long hath hée <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ght there, or elſe-where?</p>
               <p n="5">5 Whether any of the ſaid popiſh Recuſants, doe labour to ſeduce <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> withdraw others from the Religion now eſtabliſhed? Or inſtruct <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Families or children in popiſh Religion: or refuſe to entertain any, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>cially in place of greateſt ſeruice, or truſt, but ſuch as concurre with <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> in their papiſtry?</p>
               <p n="6">6 How long haue the ſaid Popiſh Recuſants abſtained from diuine <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>uice, or from the communion, as aforeſaid?</p>
               <p n="7">7 Is there any in your pariſh that retaine vndefaced, or ſell, vtter, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> verſe, any popiſh Bookes or writings, or any Bookes, Libels, or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>ings of any Secturies, touching the Religion, State, or Gouern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>nt Eccleſiaſticall of this Kingdome of England, or kéepe any Orna<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments
<pb facs="tcp:26106:8" rendition="simple:additions"/>
of ſuperſtition vncancelled or defaced?</p>
               <p n="8">8 Whether haue you any in your Pariſh, which héeretofore being Popiſh Recuſants or Sectuaries, haue ſince reformed themſelues, and come to Church to heare Diuine Seruice, and receiue the Sacraments: If yea, then who they are? And how long ſince haue they ſo reformed themſelues? And whether they ſtill remaine and abide in that conformi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie?</p>
               <p n="9">9 Is there any in your Pariſh that refuſe to haue their Children Baptized, or themſelues to receiue the Communion at the hands of your Miniſter, taking exception againſt him, and what cauſes or exceptions doe they alledge; or haue any married Wiues refuſed to come to church, according to the Booke of common Prayer, to giue God thankes after their Child-birth, for their ſafe deliuerance? And whether doe any of, or in your Pariſh, refuſe to haue their children Baptized in your pariſh-church, according to the forme preſcribed in the Booke of common Pray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er?</p>
               <p n="10">10 Whether any of your Pariſh hauing a Preacher to their parſon, Vicar, or Curate, doe abſent themſelues from his Sermons, and reſort to other places to heare other Preachers? Or whether any of your pariſh doe communicate or baptize their Children in any other pariſh?</p>
               <p n="11">11 What perſons within your pariſh, for any offence, contumacy, or crime, of Eccleſiaſticall Conuſance do ſtand excommunicate? preſent their names, and for what cauſe they are excommunicated, and how long they haue ſo ſtood, and what parſon or perſons doe wittingly and vſualli<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> keepe them company?</p>
               <p n="12">12 Whether any, not being in orders, doe execute any prieſtlie o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> miniſteriall office, in your Church, Chappell, or Church-yard, and wha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> be their names?</p>
               <p n="13">13 Whether any in your pariſh, that hauing héeretofore taken vp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on him the order of Prieſt-hood or Deacon, hath ſince relinguiſhed th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> ſame, and liues a Lay-man, neglecting his vocation?</p>
               <p n="14">14 Haue any perſon in your Pariſh, quarrelled, or ſtricken, or v<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſed any violence to your Miniſter, or haue ſtrucken or quarrelled with a<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ny other perſon within your Church or Church-yard, or demeaned him ſelfe diſorderedly in the Church, by filthy or prophane talke, or any othe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> leud or immodeſt behauiour? Or haue diſturbed the Miniſter in time o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Diuine ſeruice or Sermon, or haue libelled or ſpoken ſlanderous worde againſt your Miniſter, to the ſcandall of his vocation, or diffamed an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> of his Neighbours, touching any crime o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Eccleſiaſticall conuſance?</p>
               <p n="15">
                  <pb facs="tcp:26106:8" rendition="simple:additions"/>15 Whether any of, or in your pariſh, without conſent of the Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinary, or other lawfull authority, haue cauſed any to doe pennance, or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> be cenſured or puniſhed for any matter of Eccleſiaſticall conuſance, by any Veſtry meetings, or otherwiſe by their own authoritie? Or haue ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>en any Money or commutation for the ſame? Preſent their names that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ue done it? And who haue beene ſo puniſhed? In what manner, and vpon what cauſe?</p>
               <p n="16">16 Whether any perſon in your pariſh, doe exerciſe any Trade or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>bour, buy, or ſell, or keepe open Shoppes or Ware-houſes vppon any Sunday or Holliday, by themſelues, their Seruants, or Apprentizes, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>r haue otherwiſe prophaned the ſaid daies, contrary to the orders of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hurch of England? And whether there bée any Inne-kéepers, Ale-houſe-kéepers, Victulers, or other perſons, that permit any perſons in their Houſes, to eate, drinke, or play, during the time of Diuine Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uice or Sermon, or reading the Homilies in the forenoone or afternoone, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>pon thoſe daies?</p>
               <p n="17">17 Whether the fift day of Auguſt, and the fift day of Nouem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber, b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>eacute;e kept holie, and thankſgiuing made to God, for his Maieſties and this States happy deliueraunce, according to the ordinance in that be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>halfe?</p>
               <p n="18">18 Whether any of your pariſh, hold or frequent any conuenti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cles or priuate congregations, or make or maintaine any conſtitutions, agréed vppon in any ſuch aſſemblies? Or any that doe write, or pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liquelie or priuately ſpeake againſt the Booke of common praier, or any <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hing therein contained, or againſt any of the Articles of Religion agréed vpon, in <hi>Anno</hi> 1562. or againſt the Kinges Supremacy in cauſes Ec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cleſiaſticall, or againſt the Oath of Supremacy, or of Alleagiance, as pretending the ſame to be vnlawfull, and not warrantable by the word of God? Or againſt any of the Rites or ceremonies of the Church of England now eſtabliſhed? Or againſt the gouernment of the church of England, vnder the Kinges moſt excellent Maieſtie, by Arch-Biſhops, Byſhoppes, Deanes, Arch-Deacons, and other Officers of the ſame: affirming, that the ſame is repugnant to the Word of God, and that the ſaide Eccleſiaſticall Officers, are not lawfully ordained? Or whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther there be any Authours, Maintainours, or Fauourers of Hereſie or Sciſme, or that be ſuſpected to be Annabaptiſts, Libertines, Browniſts, of the Familie of Loue, or of any other Hereſie or Sciſme? preſent their <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>mes?</p>
               <p n="19">
                  <pb facs="tcp:26106:9"/>19 Whether any in your Pariſh haue married within the degrées by Law prohibited, or any couple in your Pariſh being lawfully married: liue apart one from the other, without due ſeparation of the Law, or any that haue beene diuorced, which keepe company with any other at Bed<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> and at Boord, and when and where were they married?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Phiſitions, Surgeons, and Mid-wiues.</head>
               <p n="20">20 HOw many Phiſitions, Chirurgions, or Mid-wiues, haue you in your pariſh? How long haue they vſed their ſeuerall ſcience: or offices, and by what authority? And how haue they demeaned them ſelues therein, and of what ſkill are they accounted to be in their profeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion?</p>
               <p n="21">21 Whether do any perſons adminiſter the goods of the dead with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out lawfull authority, or ſuppreſſe the laſt will of the dead? Or are there in your pariſh, any Wils not yet prooued, or goods of the dead (dying inteſtate) left vnadminiſtred? By authority in that behal<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e, you ſhal not faile to preſent the Executors, and all others faulty therein; and alſo how many perſons beeing poſſeſſed of any Goods and Chattels, haue dyed w thin your pariſh, ſince the xvij. day of Aprill 1613.</p>
               <p n="22">22 Whether any with-hold the ſtocke of the Church, or any goods, or other thinges, giuen to good and charitable vſes.</p>
               <p n="23">23 Whether your Hoſpitals and Almes-houſes, and other ſuch hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes and Corporations, founded to good and charitable vſes; and the lands, poſſeſſions, and goods of the ſame, be ordered and diſpoſed of as they ſhould be? And doe the Maiſters, Gouernours, Fellowes, and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers of the ſaid Houſes and Corporations, behaue and demeane them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelues, according to the godlie Ordinances and Statutes of their ſeueral Foundations?</p>
               <p n="24">24 Whether haue you any in your Pariſh to your knowledge, or by common fame or report, which haue committed, Adultry, Fornicati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, or Inceſt; or any which haue impudentlie bragged or boaſted, that he or ſhe haue liued incontinently with any perſon or perſons whatſoe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uer: or any that hath attempted the chaſtity of any woman or ſollicited any Woman to haue the carnall knowledge of her bodie, or which are commonly reputed to be common Drunkards, Blaſphemers of Gods holy Name; common Swearers, common Slanderers of their Neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bours, and owers of diſcord, filthy and laſciuious Talkers, Vſurers, ſc<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>monicall perſons, Bawds, or Harborers of Women with Childe, which be vnmarried, or conueying or ſuffering them to goe away before they haue made ſatiſfaction to the Congregation, or any that hauing
<pb facs="tcp:26106:9"/>
heretofore béene preſented, or ſuſpected of any the foreſaid crimes, haue or that cauſe departed your Pariſh, and are now returned againe? Or any which haue vſed any inchantments, ſorceries, incantations, or witch <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>aſts, which are not made fellony by the ſtatutes of this Realme, or any which haue committed any periury in any Eccleſiaſticall Court, in an Eccleſiaſticall cauſe, or which haue committed any lorgerie, puniſhable by the Eccleſiaſticall Lawes, and the procurors and abettors of the ſaide <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>fences: You ſhall truely preſent the names of all, and ſinguler the ſaid Offendors, and with whom they haue committed the ſaide offences, in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>aſe they haue not beene publikely punniſhed to your knowledge for the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>me crimes?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Tou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hing the Church-wardens and Side-men.</head>
               <p n="1">
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> VVHether you and the Church-wardens, Queſt-men, or Side-men, from time to time, doe, and haue done their diligences, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> not ſuffering any role perſon to abide eyther in the Church-yard, or Church-porch, in Seruice or Sermon time, but cauſing them either to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>me into the Church to heare Diuine Seruice, or to depart, and not di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>urbe ſuch as be hearers there? And whether haue they, and do you di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>gentlie ſee the Pariſhioners duely reſort to the Church euery Sundaie and Holidaie, and there to remaine during Diuine ſeruice and ſermon? <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>nd whether you or your predeceſſors, Churchwardens there, ſuffer any places, Feaſts, Drinkings or any other prophane vſages, to be kept in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ur Church, Chappeil, or Church-yards, or haue ſuffered to your and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>ir vttermoſt power and indeuour, any perſon or perſons, to bée tip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ng or drinking in any Inne or Victuling Houſe in your Pariſh, du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>g the time of Diuine Seruice or Sermon, on Sundaies and Holie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ies?</p>
               <p n="2">2 Whether, and how often haue you admitted any to Preach <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>thin your Church or chappell, which was not ſufficientlie licenſed? <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>nd whether you, together with your Miniſter, haue not taken diligent <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>e and care, that euery of your Pariſhioners, being of ſixteene yeares <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ge or vpwards haue receiued thrice euery yeare, as aforeſaide; and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> that no ſtranger haue vſually come to your church, from their owne <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>iſh-church?</p>
               <p n="3">3 Whether haue there béene prouided againſt euerie communion, ſufficient quantity of fine Wh te Bread, and of good and wholeſome <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>me for the Communicants that ſhall receiu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>? And whether that wine brought in a cleane and ſwéete ſtanding Pot of Pewter, or of other <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>r Mettall?</p>
               <p n="4">
                  <pb facs="tcp:26106:10"/>4 Whether were you choſen by the conſent of the Miniſter and the pariſhioners? And haue the late Churchwardens giuen vp a iuſt account for their time, and deliuered to their Succeſſors the Money, and other things belonging to the Church, which was in their hands? And are the Almes of the Church faithfully diſtributed to the vſe of the poore?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Concerning Eccleſiaſticall Magiſtrates and Officers.</head>
               <p n="1">1 VVHether doe you know or haue heard of any payment, compo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſition or agreement, to, or with any Eccleſiaſtical Magiſtrate, Iudge, or Officer, for winking at, or ſparing to puniſh any perſon for any offence of Eccleſiaſticall Conuſance, or for ſuppreſſing or concealing of any excommunication, or any other Eccleſiaſticall Cenſure, of, or a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt any Recuſant, or any other offender in the caſes aforeſaid? what ſumme of Money, or other conſideration hath béene receiued or promiſed, by, or to any of them, in that reſpect, by whom, and with whom?</p>
               <p n="2">2 Hath any perſon within your pariſh, paide or promiſed any ſum of Money or other reward, for comutation of pennance for any crime of Eccleſiaſticall Conuſance? If ſo, then with whom? When, and for what, and how hath the ſame beene imployed?</p>
               <p n="3">3 Are your Eccleſiaſticall Iudges and their ſubſtitutes Maiſters of Artes, or Batchellors of the Lawes at the leaſt, learned and practiſed in the Ciuill and Eccleſiaſticall Lawes: Men of good Life and Fame, zea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>louſly affected in Religio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>, and iuſt and vpright in executing their offices? Haue they heard any matter of office priuately in their Chambers, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out their ſworne Regiſters, or their Deputies preſence?</p>
               <p n="4">4 Do you know, or haue you heard, that any Eccleſiaſticall Iudge, Off cer, or Miniſter, hath receiued or taken any extraordinary Fées, or otheir rewards or promiſes, by any waies or meanes, directly or indirect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lie, of any perſon or perſons whatſoeuer, either for the graunting of the adminiſtration of the Goods and Chattels of thoſe that haue died inte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate, to one before another, or for allotting of larger portions of the goods and Chattels of thoſe who haue died inteſtate, to one more then to ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther: or for allowing large and vnreaſonable accounts, made by Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors or Adminiſtrators: or for giuing them <hi>Quietus eſt,</hi> or diſcharges without Inuentory or account, to defraude Creditors, Legataries, o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> thoſe who are to haue portions. And what ſummes of Money doe you know, or haue you heard, that any Eccleſiaſticall Iudge or Officer hath taken out of the ſtate of any dying inteſtate, vpon pretence to beſtow th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> ſame, in <hi>pios vſus:</hi> And how haue the ſame béene beſtowed?</p>
               <p n="5">5 Hath any Eccleſiaſticall Magiſtrate, Iudge, Officer, or any othe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb facs="tcp:26106:10"/>
exerciſing Eccleſiaſticall iuriſdiction within this your Dioces; or any Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uocate, Regiſter, Procter, Clarkes, Apparators, or other Miniſter be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longing to the ſame Eccleſiaſticall Courts, exacted or taken by any waies or meanes, directly or indirectly, extraordinary or greater Fées then are <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ue and accuſtomed? And whether is there a Table for the rates of all fées, ſet vp in their ſeueral Courts and Offices? and whether haue they ſent or ſuffered any Proceſſe to go out of the Eccleſiaſticall Courts other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe then by Law they ought? Or haue they taken vpon them the office if Informers of Promoters to the ſaid Courts, or any other way abuſed themſelues in their Offices, contrary to the Law and Cannons in that behalfe prouided?</p>
               <p n="5">5 What number of Apparators hath euery ſeuerall Iudge Eccleſiaſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>call? And wherein, and in what manner is the Country ouerburthened by them? And wherein haue they cauſed or ſummoned any to appeare in the ſaid Courts, without a preſentment or Citation firſt had? Or whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther haue they threatned any to proſecute them in the ſaid Courts, if they would not giue them ſome rewards, and what bribes in that behalfe haue they taken?</p>
               <p>If you know of any other default or crime of Eccleſiaſticall Conu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence, you are to preſent the ſame by vertue of your Oaths?</p>
               <p>The Miniſter of euery Pariſh, may, and ought to ioyne in preſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ent with the Church-wardens and Side-men, and if they will not pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent, the Miniſter may and ought himſelfe, preſent the defaultes and mines aforeſaid: and there muſt be ſeueral preſentments made to euery ſeuerall article: and the Miniſter, Church-wardens and Sworne-men, are to méete and conferre about the ſaid preſentments, and anſwering of euery of the aforeſaid Articles.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
